<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Real Estate on Federico Mutasci</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/real-estate/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Real Estate on Federico Mutasci</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 22:53:58 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/real-estate/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Pollution and Real Estate</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/hedonicpricingta/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 22:53:58 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/hedonicpricingta/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a summary of my first empirical work, my Master&amp;rsquo;s thesis in applied economics: Mutasci, F. (2019). &amp;ldquo;The Impact of Pollution on Property Price Evaluation: A Spatial Approach to Hedonic Pricing Models&amp;rdquo;, University of Milan.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The purpose of the study is to investigate one of the problems affecting the economy of the city of Taranto, namely the possibility that the deposit of polluting particulate matter (PM10) related to the presence of the former ILVA\ArcelorMittal steelworks exacerbates the decline in property values in working-class neighborhoods. The study uses a set of geolocated data on houses for sale with corresponding hedonic characteristics, including pollution levels estimated using IDW interpolation of ARPA weather station samples, controlling for socioeconomic variables. The research design enriches classic hedonic pricing models through the use of spatial lag matrices, estimating SAR and SEM models with the maximum likelihood method, demonstrating that the devaluation of homes for sale appears to be mainly related to the suburban neighborhood called “Tamburi”, located next to the steel mill.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
