<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Environmental Economics on Federico Mutasci</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/environmental-economics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Environmental Economics on Federico Mutasci</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 22:53:58 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/environmental-economics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Impact of Pollution on Property Price Evaluation in Taranto</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/hedonicpricingta/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 22:53:58 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/hedonicpricingta/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Impact of Pollution on Property Price Evaluation in Taranto&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This study analyzed the impact of pollution produced by the ex-Ilva steel plant on the housing market in Taranto and Statte. A dataset of geolocated houses for sale was compiled, with corresponding hedonic characteristics, pollution levels - estimated by an IDW interpolation of some samplings - and the percentage of residents with a university degree in each house&amp;rsquo;s area. A set of hedonic pricing models were estimated via OLS, together with SAR and SEM spatial models estimated by ML. Pollution levels and the proximity to the steel mill appear to have a negative predictive effect on property prices, while the socioeconomic environment seems to play an equally prominent role in real estate assessments. Although a correspondence has emerged between pollution, proximity to the steel plant and property depreciation, due to the lack of historical data - and with the methods hereby used - it is not possible to unambiguously establish that the worst real estate valuations in areas adjacent to the steel plant are caused by the steel plant itself.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
